kaki narase sonzai wo
rock away your existence
koko ni iru to
shouting that you are here
arata na tabi ga ima hajimaru
a new journey begins now
kawari yuku kisetsu no naka wo ikinuku tabi ni bokura
as we survived through the changing seasons
chie to tsuyosa wo te ni ireta kedo JUST LOOKS LIKE SURVIVAL GAME
we gained knowledge and strength (just looks like a survival game)
nagareteku jikan no naka ni
but the forgotten memories
okizari ni shita omoi wo
of the feelings abandoned within the flows of time
wasureta koto sura wasurete ita
have also been lost
kuzure kaketa toki kodoku wo shitte
when sinking down we learned loneliness
deaeta bokura hitori ja nai
but now we've met each other we are no longer alone
sarake dase kanjou wo banjou no omoi wo
unveil your feelings those high emotions
namidame ga unmei wo kaete yuku
those tears will change your fate
yami ni uchi narase kodou wo
pound your heartbeat against the darkness
kitto aeru yo onaji itami no hata no moto de
we're sure to meet under the same flag of pain
Shino Laugh
Shino! Let's rest a little!
I'm tired from doing nothing but
walk since this morning!
You're okay while
you can say you are tired.
It's because you still have
energy left to talk.
Nothing but quibbling as usual...
Man, I'm unlucky.
To be stuck on a mission alone
with Shino.
Hey, old lady.
Is Motoyoshi Village still far ahead?
Are you going to Motoyoshi Village?
Yeah!
Then you'll be right there
once you cross this path.
Really? Thank goodness.
But exercise great caution...
Dead people also laugh
in Motoyoshi Village...
It will be all over if
you're lured into laughing.
Naruto.
It's Motoyoshi Village.
We never imagined it at this time...
To think that in this village...
an incident too terrifying to
even talk about would occur...
In Mourning
I'm Futa Kagetsu, the chief mourner.
I'm Aburame Shino.
I'm Uzumaki Naruto!
"WILL"
Getting right down to business...
This is the will of my father,
Tobei Kagetsu.
What's this?!
My eldest son, Futa Kagetsu,
shall inherit the entire
Kagetsu family estate...
HOWEVER...
A funeral is to be held tomorrow
in Motoyoshi Village
for the head of the Kagetsu family
that owns that stretch of mountains.
I'd like you two to go.
Funeral security, huh?
Naruto can't do it.
What do you mean?!
It's because you have
the most inappropriate face
in the Leaf Village.
Say what?!
I think so as well.
But there's nobody else.
So I reluctantly decided
to add Naruto.
You'll be the main guy
on this mission, Shino.
You're probably the best suited
for this mission.
As it happens,
there's one more important mission
in addition to security.
You'll understand when
you see the will.
However, in the event that Futa raises
his voice in laughter at the funeral,
he shall lose inheriting rights
and upon consultation,
the estate shall be divided up between the
bereaved family members excluding Futa.
This will doesn't make any sense at all...
An abundance of medicinal herbs
can be picked in the mountains
owned by the Kagetsu family.
I would have no trouble getting
by for the rest of my life
if I were to inherit the estate.
But all that will all go down the drain
just by laughing at the funeral!
There's no doubt that the relatives
will be in a frenzy
trying to get me to laugh tomorrow.
To be honest,
I don't have the confidence
to withstand it.
But there is one salvation!
According to the will,
it's acceptable if I, the chief mourner,
were to appoint a substitute!
And so I commissioned the Leaf!
I asked for someone who
absolutely will not laugh!
This is no doubt the perfect mission
for Shino.
I've never seen
this guy laugh before.
Indeed, I leave it to you.
I understand.
Big Brother, dinner's ready.
This is my little sister Mai,
the youngest.
She lived together with
my father in this large home.
She was also the one at his deathbed
during his final moments.
Mai, this is Shino and Naruto.
Nice to meet you...
Let's eat!
Wait!
First, I'll taste for poison.
Taste for poison...?!
I don't think there would be anyone
among the relatives
who would go that far...
But you can never be too careful.
You've got a point.
Will you be all right, Shino?
No problem.
Even if it did contain poison,
the parasitic insects in
my body will dissolve it for me.
Parasitic... insects?
How is it?
It's all right...
Shino... laughed?!
He seems to be in very high spirits.
Which means the food is fine...
Don't eat!
Shino laughing like
this is definitely strange!
There's a laughing drug in this food!
Who cooked the food?
I did.
But the back door isn't locked...
So anyone could get in if they wanted to.
To think there would be
someone in the family
who would go so far as to poison!
Oh, no...
The drug has gotten to the insects!
No good...
They can't dissolve the drug.
Then what will we do about
the funeral tomorrow?!
This is a sight that doesn't seem
of this world!
Naruto!
Even if we were to
contact the village now,
we wouldn't be in time...
for the funeral...
So Naruto!
You...
will have to participate in the funeral
as the chief mourner's substitute!
No way...
Naruto.
I'm very uneasy,
but I'll be counting on you.
I'm also very uneasy...
Will you knock it off?! I can't sleep!
You're early, Tsukiko.
You're already here, huh?
It's dad's funeral, after all.
I came here in great haste.
Who's that kid?
This is Naruto whom I've asked to
be my substitute as chief mourner
since I'm not feeling so well.
Nice to meet you!
That's how it's going to be, so
I'll be leaving just with the greetings.
I see. But it sure is a troublesome will.
To think you can't inherit the estate
if you laugh at the funeral...
Be careful.
She's my immediate younger sister
in question, Tsukiko.
Five years ago,
she married into the next village over...
But she's probably the one
after this estate the most.
That kid will be a cinch.
Each and every one of them...
looks greedy...
What's that...?
The monk has arrived.
Why choose a monk like this,
of all people?
I have no knowledge of this!
It's a different person from
the monk at the meeting.
Don't laugh...
Laugh... Laugh... Laugh...
Now then, allow me to begin.
What was that sound?
Wasn't it the wind blowing?
Naruto, did you not raise your voice
and laugh just now?
No, I didn't!
I didn't laugh at all!
Mai, you heard it, right?
I don't know...
I only heard the sound of
barrels falling over.
Well, fine.
The funeral has only just begun.
There are still plenty of chances...
After all, the opponent is this kid
with a stupid look.
I'm saved...
Shino, huh? Thanks!
That was a close shave...
In order, please.
Then I'll go first.
Laugh... Laugh... Laugh...
No good... He won't laugh at that...
I'll give it one more push.
Don't laugh...!
I must not laugh!
This kid is nothing.
I'll kill him with laughter with
that technique of mine...
This guy also intends on
doing something, huh?
No matter what he does,
no way will I laugh!
Kiyoyasu!
— Kiyoyasu!
— Kiyoyasu is...
Here it comes...
Whatever he hits me with, I...!
I must not laugh!
Laugh... Laugh... Laugh...
A flower came out...
Don't laugh...!
Laugh... Laugh... Laugh...
Don't laugh, don't laugh, don't laugh...
I won't laugh... no matter what!
He's pretty tough...
But how long can he hold on for?
We'll make him laugh by the time
the funeral ends without fail!
That... old woman...
Dead people also laugh
in Motoyoshi Village...
It will be all over if you're lured
into laughing.
What's she doing in a place like this?
Who's there?!
Uh, oh!
Oh, it's you Mai...
With this, it's over!
We'll put this in everyone's tea!
But...
Everything will go well with this!
I don't know about that.
Who're you?!
Shino...
I heard everything...
How frustrating...
If this guy would just laugh,
I'd get some of the estate...
Thank you indeed for today.
Allow me to thank you all...
in place of the chief mourner.
With this, the mission is complete...
It looks like it will somehow
end all right.
Once the monk goes home,
the funeral will be over.
Please wait!
Please let my husband say
thank you as well. Okay, dear.
Hi! Thanks for coming today.
What's he going to do?!
It was a very nice funeral.
I was so moved!
It's tear-jerking.
That Tsukiko...
To think she would go this far.
Naruto, if you can get through this,
it will be over.
Please withstand it...!
It doesn't hurt at all!
I must remember something sad
at a time like this!
Why do I think of the Pervy Sage
at a time like this?!
All right, now is the time
to finish him off.
This is awful!
The tears are causing my face to collapse.
What're you talking about?
Your face... is right here!
No!
Oh, no...
Yes!
What?
Dad...
You're alive? Dad?!
Stop it, Big Brother, Big Sister!
Dad hates fighting!
I've thought up a good joke.
I've thought up a good joke, too.
Who are those kids...?
Where did they come from?
I'd get Dad to laugh first!
I will be the first! You stay out of it!
Stop it! Fighting's wrong!
It's as Mai says.
Fighting's wrong! Wrong.
Futa! Tsukiko!
— Futa?!
— Tsukiko?!
Now that you mention it...
Yeah... They are indeed us
from our childhood!
Oh, fighting's wrong! A kettle's a kettle!
My mom dislikes ponkan mandarins!
Groping is wrong!
Hot sake is where it's at.
My wife's secret stash is kept in a safe.
Between my legs...
Ding, dong, ding.
Yeah, ding-dong-ding.
Ding-dong.
— That's right...
— Ding-dong. Ding-dong.
— When we were kids...
— Ding. Yeah, ding-dong-ding.
— Dad made us laugh a lot
— Ding-dong-ding.
— with his silly jokes...
— Ding-dong.
— It's been a long time
— Ding. Ding.
— since I laughed at dad's jokes...
— Dong-dong-dong. Dong
— Dong-dong.
— This is it! This is what I wanted to see!
Dad!
Then who's this?
The laughter stopped.
Shino!
I'm sorry, everyone!
But I didn't think you'd all come
if it weren't my funeral...
Mai helped me out a bunch
and this was the plan.
Is that really you, Dad? You're alive.
Why'd you do this?!
In the old days,
before we knew that
the medicinal herbs we could pick
in the mountains would be profitable...
We were poor...
But we were bursting with laughter.
However, we got rich from selling
the medicinal herbs at a high price.
And when we'd open our mouths,
we'd start saying,
"Money! Money! Money!"
And the smiles vanished from
everyone's faces.
I wanted everyone to remember
what's important.
I wanted to get back
the family's smiling faces!
If I wrote that ridiculous will,
everyone would do stupid things
trying to get Futa to laugh.
And then not only Futa,
but everyone would laugh and have fun...
Happiness isn't money!
It's living while getting along
with everyone and laughing!
I remember...
Sure enough, laughter is important.
That's right...
To be honest, I'm sick of living
at the mercy of money.
You liar! You're the one saying
money this and money that the most.
There are different kinds of "money,"
and what I was talking about was...
This bell.
Could that be...?
It's the laughing drug.
It's still at an experimental stage, though.
If I made it okay to appoint
a substitute chief mourner,
Futa would summon someone
who definitely wouldn't laugh.
So I tested it out on that person first.
I was going to make everyone laugh
by putting this in everyone's tea
if nobody had laughed by
the end of the funeral.
But...
There's no point to laughter
using a drug...
It's because the people
wouldn't be laughing
from the bottom of their hearts.
Instead,
they'd be crying in their hearts...
Like me right now!
So at the end of the day,
what happened with the mission?
It's probably a success.
It's because the Hokage-sama probably
knew about the real mission.
Say, say.
You transformed into that old man, right?
Then the "Between my legs,
ding-dong-ding" thing was something you...
Forget about that.
Absolutely forget about that.
Okay, got it.
Then, fine.
Sure enough, I...
I can't get used to this guy...
kinou wa Call Sign zenbu keitai de
yesterday's call sign was broadcast all from my phone
norenai Fuzz Guitar henna kouen de
in a strange park I play the fuzz guitar without enthusiasm
Yellow Moon
yellow moon
ima mo mittsu kazoete me wo akete
even now, counting to three I open my eyes
Shadow Moon mada yume wo miteru
shadow moon, I am still dreaming
me wo mite me wo mite se wo mukeai nagara
look at my eyes, look at my eyes, as we face one another's back
me wo mite itsu aeru
look at my eyes, when can we meet?
Every Day Every Night omoi tsuku kotoba de
every day, every night, with every word I can think of
chirakatta mama no kimochi wo ima sugu
right away, my messy feelings as is
mahou no Chord Change nemurenai machi
a magical chord change in a restless city
higawari na Jazz Guitar sotto mainaa de
a daily jazz guitar played in a soft minor key
The mission this time around is
a commission from the Land of Greens
and is protection for
some traveling merchants.
This is just a D-rank mission.
Don't complain. The castle lord there
is a benefactor of mine.
Make sure you do nothing wrong.
I could manage a mission like
that asleep.
Very well.
However, I've got an important reminder
for you.
Reminder?
Make sure you don't forget to take this
with you to the site.
That is all.
Next time:
"Starting a Business!! Konoha Moving Center."